Eva Murphy

213 Crooked Cedar Way, Pendleton, SC, 20670 803-944-7265 — nagy@clemson.edu

Professional Summary

As and educator I have had the opportunity to work with students of a wide range of learning abilities. This experience has taught me how to be flexible and how to adjust my teaching skills to reach every student's interest in math. I also learned how to set high expectations for every type of student by helping each of them reach their goals, and how to teach the essential concepts from college curriculum through functional and applied strategies.

My research interest focuses on environmental data, in particular building a statistical framework for modeling near surface wind data (wind speed and wind direction) in space and time. This gave me the opportunity to learn how to build flexible models for large data sets that are non-stationary and are non-Gaussian. Furthermore, I use R programming language to clean large data sets, perform exploratory analysis and conduct statistical inference.

Professional Experience

Clemson University, Clemson, SC 29634, 2018 - Present

Mid-Carolina High School, Prosperity, S.C., 29127, 2006-2011, 2012-2018

Wade Hampton High School, Varnville, S.C., 29944, 2011-2012

Midlands Technical College, Columbia, SC, 29202, 2015 - 2020

Piedmont Technical College, Columbia, SC, 29202, 2015 - 2020

Education

Ph.D. in Mathematical and Statistical Sciences, Clemson University, South Carolina, USA, 2018-

Present

M.S. in Mathematics, University of West Florida, Florida, USA, 2014-2016

Bachelor degree in Mathematics, Babes-Bolyai University, Romania, 2002-2006

Presentations and Posters

Joint modeling of wind speed and wind direction through a conditional approach presented at:

Joint Statistical Meeting, August 2022.

- · Climate informatics, May 2022.
- · SC-ASA Palmetto Symposium, April 2022.
- Math For All Satellite Conference at Clemson University, February 2022.

Modeling of Wind Speed and Wind Direction presented at GSN Graduate Student Research Conference, May 2022.

Statistical framework for studying the spatio-temporal variation of wind speed and wind direction - Literature Review, presented at GSN Graduate Student Research Conference, June 2021

PARTICIPATIONS AND AWARDS

Chair of the Statistical Analyzes for Environmental Monitoring — Contributed Papers section at the Joint Statistical Meeting, August 2022.

Award: Best Talk Award at the SC-ASA Palmetto Symposium, April 2022.

Paper review: I participated as a reviewer for the 11th International Conference on Climate Informatics, reviewing 3 extended abstracts, March 2022.

Certificates: Completion of Clemson Thinks² Graduate Teaching Institute, Fall of 2021.

STRIVE for MORE where I was a mentor in the Near - to - Peer Mentoring Session, September 2020 and 2021.

Teaching Experience

Teacher of Mathematics: my responsibilities were: to instruct Applied Algebra, Algebra 2, Algebra 2-Honors, Algebra 3/Trigonometry, A.P. Calculus AB, Geometry, Intermediate Statistics and Probability, organize course matters and make certain that each and every content is accurately taught, create and execute project work plans and revise as appropriate to meet changing needs and requirements, manage parent and teacher meetings on a usual basis in support of make certain that parents recognize everything regarding their child's growth, supervise and tutor students taking various mathematics classes ranging from finite math to calculus, teach study skills and test taking skills, keep online records of attendance and student performance, attend professional meetings, educational conferences, and teacher training workshops in order to maintain and improve professional competence, perform administrative duties such as assisting in school libraries, and hall, cafeteria and parking lot monitoring.

Adjunct Instructor of Mathematics: my responsibilities were: to instruct MAT 101, MAT 102, MAT 140, to instruct online MAT 120 and MAT 170, keep online records of attendance and student

performance, attend professional meetings, educations conferences, and teacher training workshops in order to maintain and improve professional competence.

Graduate Teacher of Record (GTR): my responsibilities were: to instruct Precalculus, Business Calculus I, Business Calculus II, Calculus of Single Variable, tutor students taking the mathematics classes I taught. keep online records of attendance and student performance, attend professional meetings.